It will live in your heart forever!
Peter Pan is a animation, family, adventure film directed by Clyde Geronimi.
Leaving the safety of their nursery behind, Wendy, Michael and John follow
Peter Pan to a magical world where childhood lasts forever.
But while in Neverland, the kids must face Captain Hook and
foil his attempts to get rid of Peter for good.
Peter Pan (voice), played by Bobby Driscoll.
Wendy Darling (voice), played by Kathryn Beaumont.
Captain Hook / Mr. Darling (voice), played by Hans Conried.
Mr. Smee (voice), played by Bill Thompson.
Mrs. Darling (voice), played by Heather Angel.
John Darling (voice), played by Paul Collins.
Peter Pan is a 1953 American animated adventure fantasy film produced by
Walt Disney Productions and released by RKO Radio Pictures.
Based on J.
Barrie's 1904 play of the same name, the film was directed by
Hamilton Luske, Clyde Geronimi, and Wilfred Jackson.
Featuring the voices of Bobby Driscoll, Kathryn Beaumont, Hans Conried, Bill Thompson, Heather Angel, Paul Collins, Tommy Luske, Candy Candido, Tom Conway, Roland Dupreee and Don Barclay, the film's plot follows
Wendy Darling and her two brothers, who meet the eternally-young Peter Pan and travel with him to the island of Never Land to stay young, where they also have to face Peter's archenemy, Captain Hook.
In 1935, Walt Disney began considering plans to adapt
Barrie's play into an animated feature.
He purchased the film rights from Paramount Pictures in 1938, and
began preliminary development in the next year.
However, following the attack on Pearl Harbor, Disney shelved the project when his studio was
contracted by the United States government to produce training and war propaganda films.
The project sat idle in development for the rest of the
decade until it experienced a turnaround in 1949.
To assist the animators, live-action reference footage
was shot with actors on soundstages.
It also marked the last Disney film in which all nine members of
Disney's Nine Old Men worked together as directing animators.
Peter Pan was released on February 5, 1953, becoming the final Disney animated feature
released through RKO before Disney founded his own distribution company.
The film was entered into the 1953 Cannes Film Festival, Upon its release, the film
earned positive reviews from film critics and was a box office success.
Its representation of the Native Americans received retrospective criticism.
A sequel, titled Return to Never Land, was released in 2002, and a series of
direct-to-DVD prequels focusing on Tinker Bell began in 2008.
A live-action adaptation of the film was released on Disney+ in 2023.
The film explores themes of london, england, sibling
relationship, flying, becoming an adult, magic.